i want to start this off by stating the
obvious
that i'm not somebody who experiences
racism
on a daily basis and yet i am someone
who
experiences ableism on a daily basis and
because i have invisible disabilities
uh generally people don't know they're
being ableist they're not trying to be
they're not trying to be mean
they're not trying to do anything
it's just happens people we have an
assumption of how people
are and when they don't meet that we
make them wrong for it and so this
morning i woke up to
a friend someone who i love and respect
this woman is
is an amazing human being and i agree
with a lot of the stuff on on what she
posted
and she's not the one who created it but
um
in the post there is so much ableism
disguised as wokeness that i'm like
why why is it always on the neurodiverse
to change to become neurotypical like
why as a society can't we realize
that not remembering somebody's name or
not being able to recognize them isn't
necessarily racism
and a lot of times it's how our
neurodiverse brains
show up in the world both through my
autism
facial blindness and trouble with with
words until
they stick in my brain and then i can't
not repeat them
and with my tbi having memory issues and
just not being able to remember people's
names not people remember
pronunciation um and then feeling
awkward and not always wanting to talk
about that
so sometimes i do find workarounds to
remember people's
names to try like i have workarounds to
try to remember them but i also have um
workarounds to to not say them to be
like okay i know i'm not going to get
this right how can we talk to this
person without using their name
or talk around this person right because
it's like you're trying to tell a story
about them or trying to
and can't remember their name or can't
pronounce it right what you end up doing
if we're not dealing with humans as
humans it is natural that humans can't
pronounce words they didn't grow up with
and it is natural that we feel awkward
when we cannot if we make them wrong for
that
we are hurting the people who want to
help people who don't care that they're
being racist are just going to call you
whatever horrible thing comes out of
their mouth
people who want to get to know you and
want to but then every
if they mispronounce your name you're
going to think it's a slight if you're
just going to think it's a slight
it separates us instead of bringing us
together and so i just want to share
uh what the post itself said i'm not
going to put it up on the screen because
otherwise it's going to show
my friend's name everyone else and i
don't want to do that so it's just um
how to respect my ethnic name then go to
the next slide
and it's things you never say i'm never
going to remember that
do you have something shorter for that
and can i just call you blank
instead and they have little things
underneath like i'm never going to
remember that so sometimes the name can
be hard to say
but you are being dismissive and showing
that you don't value the person
when that you say i'm never going to
remember that that
is the problem that we think that if you
say i'm never going to remember that
i mean i don't pronounce i wouldn't say
it like that i would say like sorry i
have trouble with names and
um i will get it wrong a bunch before i
get it right please keep correcting me
if i know i'm gonna be interacting with
the person regularly
and it's not i mean there's a girl in
our community who
is i think she's ten now and for the
first six months we lived there i
slightly mispronounced her name and
every time she corrected me and now i
know her name i know we're gonna have to
drop a hat no problem
but because it becomes this stressful
i'm like oh wait
like i now have two names in my head her
real name and the name that i'm calling
her and i don't know which is which
right because it's like i know it's one
of these two but i don't remember which
one anyway sorry continue on with the
poster
equally inappropriate actions tapping
the person on the shoulder because you'd
never
you'd rather not get their name wrong
now people don't like to be touched and
other people are fine with it i like
being tapped on the shoulder because i
can't hear and i can't tell direction of
sound
um so if you need to get my attention it
can be really hard for me to hear and
so being tapped on the shoulder but i
don't mind a tap on the shoulder it
doesn't
doesn't trigger me in any way whereas
for other people it might and this is
where like
having blanket rules for everybody
doesn't work because it's not dealing
with people as the individual
pointing to them in a meeting instead of
saying their name
replacing their name with him her or
them and hoping you'll get away with it
how to help one repeat their name after
they introduce themselves i do this
every time and then i'll repeat it about
20 times in my head which is hard
because then you can't hear the next
thing they say
when you don't repeat their name it can
be quite frustrating because we
would like reassurance that you've heard
it and can say it correctly i know
because my name's jubilee i often i'm
like jubilee right because i'll say it
back and say julie and i
want to correct them because otherwise
people will call me julie for years
before they find out
and then feel they'll feel bad reassure
them i really want to make sure i say
your name correctly can you teach me
i think that is a great option on emails
in business make sure that you get them
right and i do that i definitely double
check when i
when i get them when i'm gonna send
something to somebody
so i post it on on her this is what i
posted
and i don't know if it's gonna go over
well but i think that she's someone who
deals in
in difficult situations and we'll hear
it for what it is hopefully
i find many of these assumptions
extremely ableist the world thinking
not remembering a name or mispronouncing
it is not being considerate or not
caring is neurotypical crap that we
could all
that we could also change and i do not
think you are doing it but the poster
does it several times
my current favorite speaker is and i'm
going to butcher this i apologize
a yeasha akanbi every time i want to
look her up i have to look up her
material instead of her because i cannot
remember her name
every time someone says her name like
actually pronounces it
i repeat it i repeat it myself about 10
times in hopes i will remember the
pronunciation and spelling
i have done this at least a dozen times
i care about this person i love hearing
what they have to say
i want to remember the name but i cannot
to have to
apologize for my brain i.e forgive me
could you remind me
but do not set them up for this
inevitability when i first when they
first tell me their name
and to not be able to use coping
mechanisms i.e using pronouns or
or wordsmithing around it or pointing to
them hurts people with different brains
and because it is applicable to this
issue
i want and i want to watch her again i
posted the problem with wokeness by
ay shedding khan so what i'm
it's hard because i know my neurodiverse
brain shows up as what is considered
racism
that i can't pronounce someone's name or
i can't keep someone's pronouns straight
which i'm much better at than i was when
i first encountered them
um
i deeply care about not hurting people
about
being less and less racist as i evolved
in life being less and less ableist
against other people and against myself
as i as i grow in life and yet this is
much like cultural appropriation which
i've yet to do a video on
but might in the future even though
again i'm not someone experiences racism
it's defeatism it's hurting the very
people
that you that we're trying to help
because
the people who want to follow those
rules are the people who
because they want to follow those rules
are going to show up in a way that
breaks them
if you feel like you're going to be seen
as a bad person when you mispronounce
somebody's name
you're going to meet people less and
less who have unpronounceable names
when you walk into a room and you see a
bunch of white people who you are going
to assume have
normal caring names and people who might
have names you can't pronounce
you're going to steer towards the ones
that are going to make you not feel
stupid and make you not feel inferior
so what we're doing is having less
togetherness
let's get to actually know you and see
what your life is like
and see you as a human being and then
you can pronounce your name again and
again
i'm sorry until my little brain gets it
right
my amazing brain is deficient in some
ways
and you know i have i have facial
blindness i facial blindness with
everyone it's really hard to watch a
show
where where there's a bunch of um a
bunch of
one type of person in it uh my brain
because it grew up with
in with white media with caucasian media
and um in 80s where there wasn't as much
diversity
um and when there was it was token
diversity it's like one black person one
asian person
so like white people i have
different colored hair so it's like oh
the blonde person the red hair person
but if there's two blonde people with
short hair i
can't tell them apart it's like it's
still not happening but
but my facial blindness is even more
with somebody of a different race
and so if i'm watching an entire cast of
black people
it's really hard to know what's all the
difference between them it's not because
i think they're all the same it's
because my brain thinks
like you just can't distinguish between
them and
i can't work on that it doesn't get
better it doesn't
if i'd seen them when i was a child i
might have the same for other races as i
do for
for caucasians but it's not
changing like it's like a lot of times
when i'm in a new group of people
my brain will put people into categories
and be like oh yes the old white guy
and if there's more than one old white
guy it's like you're either this name or
this name
um and i'll get you confused all the
time and it will just always happen
and then i i mean forget if you're
identical twins
i'm just gonna like pick the wrong one
every time
that what aisha
talks about that to have kindness is to
be radical
instead of wokeness because wokeness is
all of these rules
all of these things that are like if you
buy you if you don't do this you're
being racist if you don't do this you're
being ableist but the thing is with
ableism
everything is ableist and if you're
being if you
make something work for one group of
people you're not making it work for
another group of people
that's why i very much um think that our
neurodiversity especially autism
is part of what we're saving the world
with and it's been very much because
autistic people know how different we
are
than the neurotypicals but then each
other you meet one autistic person
you've met one autistic person
so even if we made a world that only
worked for autistic people
we would it would have to be so much
more diverse than it is
because there are people who are sensory
seeking and people who are sensory
avoidance and people who
are wanting stems and people who want
those same as people who want
deep hard hugs and people who don't want
to be touched at all
and because of people who um can
feel your your energy and your emotion
when you walk into a room
and people who can't feel their own
or make sense of their own emotions and
because of that if we make a world that
honors that diversity that's like okay
some people need
bright lights and some people we need
the dark some people need you know are
triggered by these sounds they need
silence and other people need to have
loud noise so they're not hearing all
the other noises
and to be able to work with the
individual to be able to say hey
listen i'm sorry i'm going to get your
name wrong this is me
i have brain damage i have like then i
have to disclose
everything personal about myself and
although i'm okay with that and i do do
that if you've met me in person you
probably know i'm deaf within 30 seconds
because i'm going to tell you because i
don't want to ignore you when you're
talking to me
because i care about how i show up in
the world and how i appear to other
people
and yet the energy expended in that is
extreme
to have to where i did give myself
permission to let go of
i don't need to think about every action
every word is going to affect somebody
before i say it
and the repercussions down the line i am
going to speak
my heart and when i when i mess up
when i hurt somebody tell me but
but there's a big difference between
wokeness which is like you
and i do this you broke the rule my
brain you broke the rule you need to
know the rule
right like you you can't ask someone to
repronounce their name that's racist
keep up my brain
or like don't say it quite that way or
that
approaching people as individuals and
find out what we need right if we had
those little cards i've talked about
not an actual card but some kind of
business card on
our business app card on our phones
where we can understand each other
where if i was able to give you mine you
would know that i'm deaf
in one ear and not to talk to me my
right side you would know that i forget
things in your name and it's not
personal you'd be able to put in your
name with the pronunciation so i could
practice
on my own if you want me to get it right
like there are two ways that we can get
everyone's needs met
but it's not what these blanket rules
and it's not with
racism trumps everything your ableism
trumps everything
we have to deal with each other on an
individual level and um
it takes more work it does but it also
works out better because then we can
help each other we can't help those
i mean it's going to bother me that i
didn't finish what i was going to say
about cultural appropriation
um that the people who it's meant to
help
right artists and people of the culture
it hurts because i'm not gonna buy
moccasins
from you know a uh one of the nation's
artists because i don't want to have to
explain that every time right oh no i
didn't get it at urban urban outfitters
i got it from them
and and the very people who care carry
like it's like blanket nobody can wear
it
and it's like right but and so because
it opens up the awkward conversation i'm
just not buying it we're just not
wearing it
and so we're not supporting who we
should be supporting because of the very
rule that's supposed to be there to help
them and hurts them instead
and i think most of our racism most of
our ableism is that because
it pits us against each other and it's
like oh you broke the rule and i've
gotta call you out
as opposed to hey did you know that this
rule like if somebody was like you're
mispronouncing my name and it offends me
i would deal with that i would like okay
we're gonna sit down and remember your
name i don't
you should remember in her name i'm
never gonna meet her and she's not
she's someone who probably won't will
nicely remind me
um if i did meet her and
i don't even need to be nicely reminded
when i've got your name wrong for the
dozen times
oh it's this it's like i get kind of
frustrated i'm like don't walk on my
right side don't walk on my right side
walk over here
and i don't i the other person
apologizes and it's like yeah no i got
it
when my family doesn't remember when
it's been decades that's a little harder
but it's
also it's how it is not everyone is deaf
in one ear
it's on me i'm not on me but it's my
thing to navigate in the world
these videos are longer than i normally
are because i can't record on my ipad
anymore
and so i can't record be like whoops
that was 15 minutes let's record five
minutes i'm doing these down stream yard
and then making them public
but i will be sharing as new learnings
come up and as
as i'm doing as i am creating the
projects that are creating a world that
works for everyone
there's so much in the works right now
and so much happening that
all i have to do is relax into it and
it's still
it's still hard when i do i'm like no
we're making content because i don't
need to
i can just relax into this i don't need
subs i don't need then my brain's like
oh new idea new idea
so i i and when i say i'm taking a break
from social media
i end up posting more it's how my brain
works it's like once i let it not do
anything it does everything
it's like yeah that seems about right my
brain's best friend worst enemy all in
one
love you brain thanks for hanging out
see you next time